Tolulope Babatunde

Full Stack Developer

39 Ondo street Bodija, Ibadan, Oyo Nigeria,

<u>linkedin.com/in/tolulope-babatunde-</u> 8b4266156

<u>babatundetolulopejoshua@yahoo.com</u> <u>07041147115</u>

With over 5 years experience in full stack development, I specialize in building high-performance web applications, using React, NextJs and VueJs. My projects have consistently resulted in improved performance and user satisfaction. I bring a proactive approach to project leadership and technical innovation.

Professional Experience

Full Stack Developer

Ehealth4everyone | July 2023 - Present

- Delivered 40+ high-level application enhancements improving system stability by using tools like Node and VueJs.
- Optimized the application flow which increased performance by 50% by employing best practices in coding and testing.
- Incorporated security measures in the code that dramatically reduced the vulnerability
 of the application to hacking by 95% Develop and manage well-functioning databases
 and APIs
- Reduced application downtime to less than 1% by using efficient debugging tools and adopting root cause analysis approaches
- Implemented Agile methodologies and SCRUM practices to deliver releases on time and improved the team efficiency by 35%
- Effectively collaborated with the testing team and resolved 97% of issues reported in the first phase of testing

Frontend Developer

Cytix IO | June 2022 - June 2023

 Coordinated with UX designers to create a user-friendly interface improving user experience by 60% Maintained and updated the existing web applications which enhanced the system productivity by 15%

Full Stack Developer

Freelance | September 2019 - June 2022

- Directed the integration of REST APIs with front-end code which boosted the website responsiveness by 40%.
- Employed AWS for hosting which improved the scalability and accessibility of applications, which resulted in a 30% increase in users.
- Improved application speed by 30% by upgrading the database from SQL to NoSQL using MongoDB
- Developed an effective logging mechanism to track possible application errors, reducing the debugging time by 25%.

Education

B.Tech in Physics

Federal University of Technology at Akure | January 2015

Key Skills

- JavaScript, Typescript, CSS3, HTML5
- NodeJs, React, NextJs, Vue, NuxtJs
- Git, Maven, Jenkins, Docker
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis
- Problem solving, communication
- Decision Making and Strategic Planning